Tenggis Munkhbaatar

Front-end Engineer

Email: diditrimorum72@gmail.com

LinkedIn: /in/tenggis-munkhbaatar-2a32b025a/

Phone: +49 170 9034968



FRONT-END ENGINEER

Frontend Engineer with over 3 years of experience in building reliable and user-friendly web applications. Proficient in React, Next.js, and TypeScript, with a focus on creating clean, maintainable code and responsive designs. I enjoy collaborating with teams to solve complex problems and continuously learning to improve my skills and contribute to meaningful projects.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Frontend Development: React, Next.js, Vue.js, JavaScript, TypeScript
- UI Libraries & Frameworks: Ant Design, Mantine UI, TailwindCSS, SASS
- State Management: Zustand, Redux, Context API
- Styling: TailwindCSS, SASS, LESS
- Build Tools: Vite, Webpack
- **Testing:** Jest, React Testing Library, Cypress

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Front-end engineer

Mezorn Technology LLC

Sep 2021 - May 2024 Ulaanbaatar, Mongolia

- Built, optimized and maintained 4 scalable back-office systems, managing a combined user base of over 2 million active users, using **React.js**, **Next.js**, and **TypeScript**.
- Improved team efficiency by developing 10+ reusable components, reducing development time by about 15%.
- Integrated robust testing workflows with Jest and React Testing Library
- Collaborated with design teams to implement 10+ Figma designs into responsive, productionready solutions.
- Enhanced platform performance and **SEO** visibility through optimized UI and component design
- Worked in agile environments (Scrum), collaborating closely with backend engineers to design and implement seamless APIs.

Jr. Front-end engineer

Starsoft LLC

Jun 2020 - Aug 2021 Ulaanbaatar, Mongolia

- Expanded an EduTech platform with interactive features like creating and converting presentations, live classes using Vue.js and Node.js.
- Created the back-office system for managing classes, students, and teacher accounts.

KEY PROJECTS

- **Tetgeleg (Scholarship Platform)**: Led a team of four to develop a dynamic back-office system with customizable user roles and menu items, handling over 1 million requests and supporting 500,000 active users // tetgeleg.mn
- UbEats (Office Food Delivery System): Built a back-office system for a platform with 50K downloads and 10K active users, enabling corporate meal ordering // ubeats.mn
- UbCab (Uber-like Platform): Contributed to refurbishing the back-office and main webpage of a
 highly successful project with over 1 million active users and 45,000 drivers, focusing on
 performance and user retention // ubcab.mn
- **Bidend (Auction Platform)**: Developed an interactive auction platform with real-time bidding from scratch using Socket.io // <u>bidend.mn</u>
- Mezorn Landing Page: Translated Figma designs into a responsive, SEO-friendly company website using Next.js and TailwindCSS // mezorn.com
- Lann (Gaming Item Exchange Marketplace): Built a management system for peer-to-peer gaming item trading platform, achieving 1K users in the first week // lann.market

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Software Engineering

Mongolian University of Science and Technology

Sep 2017 - Jun 2021 Ulaanbaatar, Mongolia

School Education

Mongolia-Russian Joint School

Sep 2006 - May 2013 Ulaanbaatar, Mongolia